Uh, you and I can do it between the two
of us.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Let me know how I can help. I'm
I'm here.
>> Yeah. Good morning, Kathy.
>> Good morning, Kathy. And thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Uh, well, good morning
everybody. Uh, this is Dominic Zerlo
from the Department of Health. We are uh
starting the meeting, of course, but
we're letting people in in the lobby.
So, we'll give it just a minute so that
people can join on in. Uh, in the
meantime, of course, we do have our
information for the board and for
contact information. Uh if you have
questions or if there's written comment
or public comment that you want to make
and don't get to do it during the
meeting for any reason, whether it's not
able to uh uh turn on your mic or if uh
you have a think of something after the
meeting, you can send it to our program
website which is medical.silocybin
dooh.nm.gov
gov and you can do that uh up until 5:00
on Monday and then we will include that
in the records for the meeting. Um just
as a reminder for everybody, it does
take a few days, usually between 5 to 10
business days for recordings and
documents to be available on our
website, but we will be posting both uh
the recording of this meeting and the
documents to the website. And I'll also
use that as the reminder that this
meeting is being recorded. Um so as a
part of that uh we do not have cameras
on except for the organizers and the
presenters. And the part of the reason
for that is so that we don't have any
unexpected uh images in the background
uh which has unfortunately happened for
uh not in our meetings but in other
meetings in other places. And so we have
that and as well what we have discovered
is when there are a lot of people on and
we have people in some areas of the
state where there is poor internet if we
have the the cameras on for everybody a
lot of people end up losing some of
their internet capability and keep
dropping off and joining in and we want
to ensure people are able to at least
participate as much as possible. So with
that I will turn it on over to the chair
who is Dan Jennings. So Dan, uh, go on
ahead and take it away.
>> Perfect. I really appreciate that. Uh,
Dominic, thank you very much for having
me here today and I want to really
appreciate all of y'all that have come
on today on Friday to be on our first
committee meeting here for the research
and continuous improvement committee. Um
just to kind of do a little bit of
housekeeping also for myself. I would
love to, you know, spend this first like
20 minutes of our time here today with
any kind of introductions. And first I
would love for the DO team that's here
to just kind of introduce. I mean you've
already met Dominic and I would like for
them to if they would like to introduce
and then during that time if you would
like to introduce yourself too I would
like you to get in the queue just use
the raise hand feature that's there in
your team's view and go ahead and raise
that if you'd like to introduce
yourself. You can also use the chat
feature to do so as well. If your
microphone may not be working uh you'll
be unmuted. just let us know your name,
your affiliation, where you're from, uh,
and just very short comment would be
fine. We're going to do probably about
one minute or so per introduction so we
can kind of finish this up in the first
20 minute beat of this uh, committee.
So, if you wouldn't mind, uh, do team,
please introduce yourself.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Hi, my name is Jorge Gonzalez. I
am the, uh, program manager for the
medical psilocyber program.
Morning everyone. My name is Kathy
Ajerry and I'm an IT project manager and
I support the Center for Medical
Cannabis and Psilocybin with all of
their IT related uh projects.
>> Good morning everyone. I'm Brenda
Martinez. I'm the deputy director at the
center for medical cannabis and
psilocybin. Glad to be here.
>> Great. and Jorge if you'll go ahead and
start unmuting. Thank you. [snorts]
>> Sure.
Brenda, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself.
>> Good morning everyone. I'm Brenda
Burgard. I am on the advisory board for
education and training. I'm an LPCC
and I've been living here in New Mexico
for many decades. So, I'm really
familiar with um the culture and um I am
actually a graduate of NMSU and UNM and
the Southwestern College of Santa Fe.
>> Dan, your your mic has been unmuted.
Please unmute yourself.
>> Hello. It's been an honor to be uh able
to speak at some of these different
events. My name is Daniel. I'm from uh
the wonderful state of Oregon. Um the
licensed psilocybin testing laboratory
out here and I just feel like with three
years in the legal market of testing and
previous to that I did a I'm a cannabis
laboratory but we're also full
environmental laboratory. I just um I'm
a little bit of an activist and I'm just
trying to help you guys with any
questions you have from somebody that's
been in the industry for a while.
Gregory, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself.
>> Good morning.
It's cold and snowy.
Uh my name is Gregory Evans. I'm
independent researcher. Um
my the core of my work related to
research and continuous improvement is
um using an um HLC and massspec to
normalize a PCN analysis of biomass so
that we can establish unified dosing and
then through that leverage uh full
alkoid profiles that could be
specifically targeted for unique
therapies. Um whereas somebody with PTSD
may respond better to uh one uh cheotype
rather than somebody with treatment
resistant depression or somebody having
acute anxiety may may respond to a
different chemical profile.
>> Eight, your mic has been uh enabled.
Please unmute yourself.
>> Good morning. I'm Kate Hawk. I'm in
Santa Fe. I'm going to as many of these
meetings as possible. It's this
incredible process. Um I've been a
trauma therapist for 40 years. I've been
involved professionally with
psychedelics since the 1980s in all
kinds of different ways. And um I'm
interested in research. I'm doing uh
really focusing on expan uh death and
dying and expanded states of
consciousness.
um doing a research project surveying
the whole scene in that field and now
there's a lot happening and um also host
the Santa Fe Psychedelic Society
meetings here. Um just really happy to
be with you this morning. Thanks
>> James. Your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself.
>> Thanks Greg.
>> Thank you sir. Appreciate you. Dan,
hello and everybody and and Dominic. My
name is James Brown. I have a doctorate
in pharmacy from the University of New
Mexico here. I have a very extensive
network and background in psychedelics
as well as psilocybin and silosin. Um
I've been trained in Oregon um
underneath their program and so I'm very
excited to bring that to this team. Um I
I'm really just excited to see us look
at this research. I think this is a very
important committee. Um this is a a huge
background. We need to look at so many
important things in these core elements
of data collection is going to be very
big and I know Dan's over that and so am
I and I'm looking forward to that and
and looking forward to our guidelines
and what we can recommend as a group.
Um, and that's why I'm here today is to
to be that advocate, but also to share
what I know and just to make sure we're
all safe and we have those harm
reductions and we have what we need to
make New Mexicans have access to this,
but also are safe using it. So, hope
everybody's having a great, safe, warm
day. Take care.
Denali, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself.
Good morning everybody. Um grateful to
chair um and to the department. I'm a
little bit sick this morning so sorry
for that. Um I my name is Denali. I am
uh the director of strategic support for
New Mexico uh for the healing advocacy
fund, which is a nonprofit that supports
state regulated access to psychedelic
healing and with a specific focus on
ensuring accessibility, affordability,
and equity in those programs. And I'm
based in Los Cusus, um where I grew up
and where my family lives. and um just
really grateful to the committee and and
eager to be a support however we need.
But I'm especially grateful or excited
to hear uh the chair walk us through um
the scope of this committee and what
your goals and hopes are. So, we'll be
listening attentively.
>> Katherine, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself.
Hello and good morning. My name is
Katherine Waro. I am a licensed
professional counselor in Los Cusus, New
Mexico. I've been doing psilocybin
assisted therapy work for a few years.
Um I'm very excited about this program.
I'm excited about this subcommittee. Um
I'm here mostly like Denali to listen to
offer um you know any of my expertise if
it's relevant. Um otherwise I'm just
grateful that we're all here. Thank you
everybody for your time and effort on
this project.
>> James, your mic has been enabled. Please
uh unmute yourself.
Hello and good morning everybody. My
name is James and I'm from Arizona and
I'm associated with the Arizona
Department of Health Services and I've
been assisting with psychedelic and
psychoactive related clinical trials.
Um, I went to grad school at the UW, uh,
Madison, a school of pharmacy where I
got my pharmaceutical sciences degree
with an emphasis in psychoactive
substances. I think that this, uh,
committee is absolutely incredible.
Continuous improvement and research is
pivotal and I think we can all agree
that access is very important, but in
order to obtain access, we need data and
we need to be able to uh, be harm
reductionists as a team. So, I'm really
excited to learn from everybody and um
yeah, thank you very much for your time.
>> Shane, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself.
>> Yeah, my name is Shane McDaniel. I'm a
fifth generation New Mexican. Uh my
family uh homesteaded here in Eastern
New Mexico before we were even a state.
Um, I'm a psychedelic assisted therapy
integration coach. Um, I'm also a
amateur micologist. Uh, I have
experience um with uh a lot of the
equipment necessary to do the testing.
Um, I I I'm worked in the semiconductor
industry and I used chromatography a lot
in the semiconductor industry at Intel
and Rio Rancho. Um I'm also uh
recent he recently healed um
from a bunch of different uh mental
health issues um from my gain. I went
down to Ambio uh in Mexico and received
that. And part of that um process was it
gave me a passion to not only find out
about
psychedelic medicines and therapies, but
to make it my life mission um to
help others receive the healing that I
was able to receive.
And I'm just so grateful for all of you
and and the state of New Mexico for
taking up this effort and I just can't
wait to
get this going. And again, thank you to
all of you guys. And one other quick
thing is I don't have access to the
chat. It won't let me enter chat. So if
there's somebody that can tell me
how to fix that, it just says I need to
join the meeting and I'm in the meeting.
So,
>> Shane, not sure on that, but we're going
to be reading the, uh, important
messages in the chat verbally. So, uh,
>> well, I can read the chat. I can read
the chat. I just can't
>> Uhhuh.
>> I just can't enter like I can't make a
entry.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I'll look into that, Dominic.
>> Thank you, Kathy.
>> Thank you, guys.
Desba, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself.
>> Uh, y I'm Desba and I am a part of the
psilocybin advisory board. Just hanging
out, listening with y'all. Thank you.
>> And with that, we do have an
introduction in the chat from Tessa
Capel and it says, "Good morning
everyone. I am Tessa Capel with a PhD in
experimental psychology. worked with
Larry Leeman on psychedelic research and
love to contribute to the research
committee. We also have a uh a few
resources included uh by Dan Houston. Um
and thank you and Denali says
congratulations Shane. So glad you had
the healing experience.
So uh with that is there anyone else for
introductions? Oh
>> there there's one more. Yep.
>> Thank you Har.
>> Ben, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself.
Hi, good morning. My name is Ben Edwards
and uh I work in soil micology and have
done soil restoration for three decades
and have had a relationship with
psilocybin and indigenous ceremonies for
most of my life.
Great. Well, thank you everybody for the
introductions. I see no other hands up
for introductions. So, I really
appreciate all of you being here today
and sharing your story and why you're
here. Um, and uh, Dominic, if you
wouldn't mind, we can go right on into
the first slide of the presentation. Um,
and just to let everybody know that as
we go through this, this is the first
beat that we'll probably do with the
subcommittees that uh, be running will
be first 20 minutes will be for
introduction purposes. So, I appreciate
everybody being able to do that. I do
want to kind of use also this time to
just remind kind of what our purpose and
responsibilities are for this specific
subcommittee. Uh the idea is that this
subcommittee is to ensure that provider
preparation and research activities,
harm reduction and program evaluation
for that medical psilocybin program
services grounded in scientific
evidence, ethical standards and
continuous quality improvement
principles. So that's kind of the key
mission for us to exist. I do want to
also put out that if you're interested
in if you're very specific into other
committee actions, meaning that if
you're interested in like what dosage
would look like, if you're interested in
what patient qualifications would look
like, if you're interested in
cultivation, those kind of things,
equity, please know that there are
separate committees for those
activities. So this committee doesn't
take the responsibility away from those
committees. This is a committee that
we're going to focus on these kind of
things the responsibilities that we've
set up for these core and I would love
as we go through this if you're like hey
I think that we need to modify scope or
clarify scope or anything like that I'm
very interested in hearing about that as
well but these are kind of where we
wanted to kind of start with just to
kind of see where we can like launch
from. So the responsibilities that we'll
be talking about kind of first are core
data elements that we would need to look
at from a research evaluation standpoint
from the patient and provider
perspective. Outcome monitoring
including adverse event reporting
standards, ethical research practices
and evaluation frameworks. And then also
this subcommittee we would like to focus
on uh the harm reduction and quality
improvement practices that will go
through this program including risk
screening, medication interaction
guidance, emergency preparedness and
crisis uh response, the informed consent
and patient education materials and that
would also go into the community when it
comes to this kind of harm uh reduction
and then mechanisms for updating the
standards as new evidence emerges. So
that's kind of the focus that we're
going to be looking at to get started.
And again, if anybody is like, hey, I
think you've missed the point, you
missed the mark, you've added too much,
or this is something that we don't need
to get involved with. I would love, of
course, to hear that feedback as well.
But that's kind of where we can start.
We can add the a list of things as we
go, but this is kind of where we wanted
to start with on a core. Um, so for our
next kind of beat for this committee, I
did want to set up some kind of core
norms that we would follow. I know that
a lot of other committees call them
bylaws and we can formalize them into a
bylaw structure if necessary. But for
first meeting, I really just wanted in
this next 20 minute beat to talk about
what the core norms that we want to
focus on in this group. And I would like
for everybody that's part of this
committee today to be able to share what
you're thinking about what kind of core
norms we would need to have. There's a
couple of ways that I would like to do
it. It's a little easier if you do type
it into the chat box because then it's
easy for me to kind of copy and paste
that as we go because they're put in
your words. I don't like to take what
you say and try to summarize it
sometimes and something I might miss.
So, if you do have some time and
ability, and if you're not able to,
that's fine. We'll work together on uh
opening up the microphone for you. But
if you can type into the chat box a norm
that you would like to this group to
focus on. And like I said, we'll spend
this next 20 minutes doing that. If you
as you're seeing those norms come across
in the chat box, if you're like, that's
something that we need to focus on and I
really want to put my vote behind it,
just use your little reaction bubbles
that are on that chat message. you'll
see it whenever you see the thumbs up or
the heart emoji or anything like that.
And that way we know that hey we're kind
of hitting that norm is resounding with
a lot of people and again if you're like
nope that norm doesn't work for me I
don't want to or I want to elaborate on
it raise your hand let's unmute you and
share a little bit more. So again if you
can chat great and if you can vote using
that great and if you can't let's go
ahead and raise hands and get that out
in voice form. So, we'll spend the next
20 minutes here until about uh 9:40
working on that activity just first.
>> And Dan, just uh to be consistent, we
did have one other individual who
introduced themselves in the chat. So,
that was uh Meredith uh McBranch who
says she is a a psychology student
interested in pursuing a graduate degree
in clinical psychology and PAT and
especially interested in the research
side of it. Also, we did figure out that
one of the things that sometimes does
happen if people are not able to utilize
the chat and be able to get it get into
there is if they are using a link that
was forwarded to them rather than going
through the link that they had through
the registration. And so if if you have
that issue, let us know uh and we will
see what we can do. But that's part of
why we do need to have everybody
register and use the links that they
sent for the registration and we will do
our best to be able to help with that.
So, thank you. And back to you, Dan. And
of course, people who uh thinking about
what the norms are.
I'm not seeing anything in the chat box.
So, I'll go ahead and if it might be
easier for people, just raise your hand
if you wanted to share a norm that you
wanted this group to focus on. And a lot
of other groups have used norms such as
the committee voting uh how that might
look before we would take something from
this committee and move it forward into
the board as a whole. Other uh norms are
part of what bylaws have been are the
qualifications of who can actually make
those votes that they would have to be a
resident in Mexico. These are some of
the things that we wanted to kind of
focus on. Oh, first question um James
Brown brought up in the chat meeting
timeline every two weeks. My
intentionality is to be able to schedule
this in such a way that it's regular and
expected. Uh every two weeks is what I
would hope but that will also uh we'll
have to revolve around other groups so
that I don't want to have our group at
the same time as somebody else's group
so you can't go to both of them and also
our uh board will be meeting. So, at
this point, I would like to see if we
could do the 23rd at the same time of
January, so we could kind of keep on
that cycle, but uh we'll be able to put
that update out as we kind of go, but
that's my intentionality. And then we
can start to put it onto the schedule as
a regularly occurring event for you.
>> Dan, we do have one hand up. Perfect.
Thank you.
Uh Dan Houston, who your mic has been
enabled, please unmute yourself to
speak.
Um hello there. Uh I'm here today from
Oregon because uh I just love research.
I love some of the information that we
have found out here in Oregon by doing
little experiments at the laboratory. Um
I just really feel like there's a
portion of um science slash um
experiments that uh needs to be more
readily available information more
readily available to people and I just
want to make sure that people there
understand um you know difference
between psilocybin and solosin and also
just different things like uh here in
Oregon uh after a lot of this research
church uh the way uh consumers have been
consuming the product have changed
dramatically
um you know and what started a lot of
what started this was I feel like we're
doing mythbusting type stuff um when it
comes to this research and in a group of
people it'd be almost interesting to see
in this group of people if that hasn't
seen my research um to see a show of
hands you know type of situation like uh
how many people believe it's better to
boil fail your uh tea when you're making
psilocybin or it's not you know stuff
like that. So I just wanted to say that
a lot of the research I posted
helps uh therapy assisted uh assistance
when you're trying to dose people
especially understanding psilocybin and
solosin and the difference between the
two.
>> Thank you Dan. Uh I have a quick
question. Did you have anything that you
want to contribute to the norms of the
group how we might be able to interact?
Uh, I've been trying to think about that
and I'm actually I'm a little bit
puzzled. I'm not
>> No worries. Um,
>> I'll keep thinking about it.
>> Thank you very much. Appreciate it. I do
have uh some information in the chat
there that I'll share as well. Uh uh
there Kate talk. It said open to input
from everyone but stay on topic and
voting by New Mexico residents. So um we
have kind of two kind of norms so far
that have been bubbled up from that.
Again, if anybody else has other norms
of how we should interact in this group
um as we move forward and other
meetings, I would love to hear that as
well.
And I see a hand from Gregory Evans.
>> Gregory, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Dan, I'm having trouble kind of putting
the thoughts into words. Um, but
[clears throat] what I really want to
see in this committee and others
is
we have a lot of really intelligent
people that have a lot of resources and
between the meetings I think we should
be doing work and like how are we going
to like decide the work that needs to be
done, who does the work, how do we track
that and bring it back to the committee
for reporting and community
like uh peer you.
>> I like that.
>> It absolutely makes perfect sense. I'm
going to uh summarize it myself as
homework, but no, I'm not to not to
minimize that, but exactly. This is kind
of the whole thing is that we want to
have a way that between meetings, there
is going to be something. And I hope
that at the end of today's meeting, I do
leave you with dare I say again the word
homework, but some things to basically
take away from this meeting and to come
back because I did start with some
information to share with y'all. But I
would like to have this I don't know I
know that in a two-hour meeting it's too
hard to just see something on the screen
and then say okay I can give you you
know clarification or information or
vote thumbs up or down or something like
that. But I do want to at every meeting
to say here's kind of the unresolved
work we need to do and then what we can
do to move forward. So thank you very
much for sharing that. That's a very key
point.
>> And Dan, we have a couple of other items
in the chat uh from James Brown.
Literature research broken down into
areas primary, secondary, tertiary and
include all three types with focus on
the primary. Uh, Greg of course uh
saying give me all give me all the
homework. Uh, Denali, in addition to
voting being restricted to Mexico
residents, a conflict of interest, a
media clause of some kind would also be
valuable. And then of course uh James, I
love the amazing people on this
committee with the different states
involved and see all members have a vote
on the committee.
be the uh I'm just kind of keeping some
notes here as I go on this one. So that
that way that's my homework is to kind
of take the norms that y'all are
bubbling up and to say great now let's
put this together into something that we
can go forward with because like I said
at this meeting today we're not going to
exit the end of the two hours and say
great I've got something to take to the
rest of the board and we're going to
vote on it. So today is essentially just
a way to kind of share some information
that I've gathered so far to give us
something to chew on if you will and
then to see if we're heading in the
right direction as uh as I'm sharing
this. I want to hear directly from y'all
on those things. So
and uh any others that might come up now
at this because I don't want to belabor
a point if we've already kind of shared
everything and we can move on to the
next beat which would be kind of our our
bulk here.
I'm going to make one more uh kind of uh
announcement on this is that and Dominic
you put that slide back up that has the
email address uh for us as well because
again uh just kind of like uh what uh
Gregory had said was like hey I need to
uh be able to kind of share information
between meetings this email address is
the best one to use meaning share
everything from this email address. Uh
what I would love for you all to do is
if you do send something and it is
dedicated for this committee, just make
sure you put something about like
research and continuous improvement or
or something that kind of shows that
it's going to go to this committee so
that I get it forwarded to me. So if you
think of things after this meeting,
anything, please share it to that email
address. So, uh, and actually, yes, the
idea that I'm trying to do is to get
those agendas as we're going to have
these meetings published on that. So,
and I like the idea that RER is putting
into the chat here about this about the
agenda published 24 hours ahead and the
task priorities and backlog tracking uh,
so that we can kind of say here's the
things that we've worked on, but we
haven't resolved yet. So, thank you. And
we have a couple of more uh comments in
the chat and I can read from Kate Hawk.
Definitely appreciate expertise from
other states. Maybe have certain people
as committee members versus anyone
listening.
Uh other committees have had various
ways of identifying who votes.
And then uh Dominic entered the email
address for you to send your comments if
you have others. Uh that's in the chat
as well. The program website and the
advisory board website. And then Gregory
Evans also added, "I'll suggest RACI as
a solid acronym."
>> I like the acronym. Thank you. Yeah, it
makes it a little bit easier instead of
I mean, we'll just have to be careful.
We'll use a lot of acronyms, I'm sure,
in this, but uh we'll this is a good way
to kind of instead of the mouthful of
research and continuous improvement. So,
so thanks thanks for the thumbs up on
that one, too, or put that out. So, uh,
again, we'll, uh, we'll kind of have
this amount of time dedicated for this
at the top to talk about norms and to
reenter back on norms again when we come
back again to another meeting. But if
you have any thoughts that you have in
the meantime, please send them to that
email address. And so, now we'll kind of
move into a little bit of the bulk of
the presentation that I had for you
today. And what I've been doing is kind
of gathering myself up some of the best
practices and research that I found out
there to kind of go back to what uh Dan
had said in the chat about focusing on
primary research first. As much as I've
tried to do, I have tried to find some
primary research information for you.
Now, you don't have to write all this
down or take snapshots because this will
be posted at the end of the cycles of
meetings that we've had. So, don't worry
about it. You'll be able to access this
as a handout whenever the do team has
this posted up on the page uh the
psilocybin uh page. So you can find this
later but that way kind of the homework
is take a look at some of the research
that I have found and I would love for
you hearing your feedback from the
research. So we'll bring some of that
feedback back to the next meeting to say
this is something that we should keep.
this is something that we should
question or take off. And these are some
research that I've missed. I've had a
blind spot on. So that should be added
to it. Uh so I'm going to show you just
a few slides of the research that I
found. The first one that I would love
to really focus on is as we move through
this entire system from start to finish
and we start to actually get the medical
psilocybin program started up. I feel
it's very important as we work on
continuous quality improvement that we
have a mechanism in where we can kind of
gather people together and in a way to
kind of share the researches and best
practices and such and kind of grow the
community. Uh I'm going to just make a
kind of a pitch there for project echo.
I've worked with them many years and
project echo is amazing tool to kind of
get the the diffusion of information
into communities and build best
practices and bring those things back.
So I just again as we're doing this this
is something that I would like to make
sure that people you know we have some
tools that we can utilize and project
echo is a homegrown program as well. So,
uh, it's just something that we might
look at as a potential, uh, for this to
get practitioners, growers,
facilitators, etc. into something where
they have ongoing best practice
dissemination. Then I've got a few other
links here for some information about
clinical outcomes and such on this page.
Uh, if you'll go on to the next page,
I've got a few more uh, slides. So,
again, I'm not going to belabor the
points of all these. You'll be able to
read them. As Dominic said, it could
take between five to 10 business days to
get these posted, but I would love for
you all to be able to look at them, take
a look at them, and come back and give
me some feedback on what you think.
And uh if Don, you might go to the next
slide there.
We also have a couple comments in the
chat. You want me to read those?
>> Okay. Uh Denali had to step away, but
she'll be back in at 10 o'clock. back
shortly. Uh, Katherine Waro, I'm
grateful for input from other states,
but do feel it is important that New
Mexico folks make the final decisions. I
will have to leave on the hour, but
we'll be watching the recordings to see
what I missed. And then Dominic wrote,
"Please remember it will take between 5
to 10 business days to have documents
and videos posted." Great.
>> And and my apologies on the delay, Dan,
as is usual with virtual. No, the system
decided as I tried to switch things to
make me sign back into our system. So,
it took me an extra minute, but I'm I'm
back in. I could hear everything. I just
couldn't actually do any functions. So,
>> that's okay. So, if anybody is having
any technical problems with Teams, don't
don't forget that we are all having some
problems sometimes, too. So these are
some regulations that I gathered from
around uh the US and including in
Canada. Uh the Alberta uh health
government system there has utilized uh
psilocybin as a uh as a tool as well and
has a permission granting system. So I
put uh some links here that to take a
look at as well. Uh the next slide
please.
Then when we talk about code of ethics
and equity, I've gathered a few uh tools
that I've found throughout as well. Uh
including APA's code of ethics to take a
look at and some of the ethical code
that was built in the Colorado model as
well as Alberta's incident reporting
guidelines as a way to kind of take a
look at when to uh submit critical
incidents or just a duty to notify.
There's also Oregon's code of ethics
bill of rights for uh the clients. And
then there was a indigenous communities
working group report that came out of
the Colorado group that I really thought
was kind of important to to review and
to to come from. Next slide please.
Then when it comes to some of the uh
information for patients and we're
screening informed consent. So there's
client services guide which really it
gives a lot of the details. So we can
look at this as as a model. we can see
if we wanted to build upon that uh if
for New Mexico same thing with client
intake form and then a couple of things
that I wanted to kind of hit on the risk
screening because uh there have been
some contra indications when it comes to
psilocybin so I know that that's coming
up in other groups uh when it comes to
dosing and patient qualifications and
such but if we want to make sure that we
have all the research to kind of back
some of those things up I wanted to
gather a few so a few things that there
are u there's a mood disorders
questionnaire that uh may is a
possibility psilocybin interaction
checker um which is I believe a paid
site but again it's just a tool to take
a look at for us there's also the colia
suicide scale and the mood disorder
question I think I just put it in there
twice there unfortunately but so this is
something to that we would look at as
maybe potential like warning signs for a
patient that would be interested in uh
moving into the medical psilocybin. The
next page, please.
And then when it comes to uh making sure
that we're tracking and being efficient
and effective with the the medical
program, there's a few things that we
could look at as uh self-reported scales
for patients, including depression
scales. Uh there's a couple of different
tools. These uh most of these are uh
self-reporting tools but uh this would
be a way to kind of track ongoing
interaction followup integration to see
if it is finding improvement uh with
somebody with dream uh drug resistant uh
depression. Then there's the PTSD
checklist, the PCL 5. Uh for end of
life, there's a uh GAD uh general
anxiety disorder uh survey as well. And
then for the uh uh for somebody who's on
uh medical psilocybin for substance
abuse, then there are other tools such
as uh the timeline followback tool to
take a look at to see if that is
lessening substance use. And then um
couple of different tools that I was
interested in looking at to see if the
effect of psilocybin w has has actually
been a dose that triggered
a mystical experience or brings a
challenging experience. So there are two
vetted tools out there the MEQ and the
CEQ for those two things. And then
there's also adverse events. So, uh, for
adverse events, there's already a
standard classification criteria, the
CTCAC, that's used a lot for clinical
trials, especially in cancer treatment,
and is exhaustive of all of the
different adverse effects and a rating
scale across each one of those as well.
Uh, next slide, please.
And then I believe, yeah, this I believe
is our last slide for the research. And
so to look at harm reduction education,
um some of the things that we've heard
from uh the field were that there needs
to be training for uh EMS law
enforcement and health uh mental health
professionals. Uh MAPS has done a
wonderful job of creating training
modules. Um as a matter of fact, they
are no charge. And so I wanted to bring
those up to kind of show this could be a
tool that could be utilized in this. Um
there's also uh fact sheets on
psilocybin assisted therapy. Um and then
the last one is kind of a short guide
for navigating post psychedelic
difficulties that could be uh client
focused uh link. So just again this part
I just wanted to kind of share this is
some of the like background research
that I've tried to do to prepare for
this committee uh to kind of share with
everybody. Again, I don't it right now.
I know you're thinking like, "Oh,
there's thousands of other things that I
would love to add to this list or
there's I would like to take a look at
these links." And so, just I would let
you know this will be posted again after
this meeting. Uh again, 5 to 10 days.
Please, you know, keep an eye out for
those announcements and then you could
take a look at them. But in the
meantime, the kind of homework there
would be I would love for y'all to share
through the email link uh the email
address for medical psilocybin any other
tools or research or anything that you
want to be directed to the RACI uh
committee. And so that way we capture
it. A lot of times it's hard to capture
it right in the chat box, but if you do
send it through the email address, then
we'll definitely have a record of it
getting to us. So, uh, that's where I'm
going to take a pause and just kind of
open this back up for everybody else,
uh, to to kind of be able to share. Open
up your mics if you need to raise your
hands and such.
>> Okay. And James, we do have or I'm
sorry, Dan, we have uh James Hassobe has
actually included in the chat a an
extern external resource for drug
science independent evidence-based
organization founded by Dr. David Nut
and then has the link there. Um and then
James Brown has posted as we read
through the various information remind
everyone on the bias and motivation for
each one. And that's actually a great
reminder whenever reading any kind of
research or uh checklists or items like
that.
>> Yeah. And that's exactly why I wanted to
kind of share this is because I would
love to hear from people that are
experts in the field to be able to come
back push back against any of these and
say this should not be included because
of this reason. Uh or if there's any
other information that you would like to
share because of that. So again, you
don't have to if there is certain
information you'd like to share and
you're like, I don't want to put that
publicly, you can always share it
through that email link as well and we
will include it in uh our considerations
of the committee too. So that's why
that's why for this moment I just wanted
to kind of share some of the research
that I have been finding and then just
as a starting point. So again we can
add, eliminate, edit, put notes on and
such like that from there. Any other
comments or thoughts from the committee?
A question out of the chat from Gregory
Evans. Do we have any conversation
developing around grant funded or
private research programs that could
emerge in the state and is there a type
of involvement this committee will have
around that? Um that part of the scope
is something that I would like to have
further conversations around especially
with the rest of the board and the do
staff on this. Um so that that is a
valid one and that's on at the end of
this presentation. I do have that as
kind of a future thought to think about.
So thank you.
Okay. And
I'll just kind of as a as a former
educator, I always do wait time. So I
always like to just pause for a little
bit because sometimes it takes sometimes
to type in the chat or to, you know, get
thoughts together. So forgive me while I
just pause for just a moment here for
that reason.
And you can still think about this and
comment on this, but I'd love to move on
to our next part that I'd like to share
with you, and that is some of the data
collection system. Uh, and so Dominic,
if you might go to the next slide. And
so this uh, forgive me for sometimes
geeking out um, but this has been my
life for the last 20 some odd years is,
uh, creating data tools. I spent about
28 years in public education doing uh
student reporting, creating databases
and such. So, this is something that
I've really thought about a lot. Again,
this is very rudimentary. I call it very
drafty, but it's something that I again
wanted to put out as a way for us to
chew on. And so, since everybody's here
and being able to see this, it gives me
the chance to kind of explain what my
thought process was was this. and then
hear back from the field about things
where I've been blind and haven't
thought about certain things or things
that we need to consider or add or
consider removing. So the first set of
fields would be something I feel in data
collection would be just the
demographics and some of the social
determinants. So, as we're looking to
create data collection systems, first
one patient identifier, it's some form
of an anonymous unique ID for this
individual, the date of birth, sex at
birth, gender identity, and race,
ethnicity, um, as well as this kind of
information would help us to find
equity. Some of them I've explained in
there too is that their biological sex
does affect some of the
pharmarmacinetics of uh, psilocybin. So
just some of the ideas that we wanted to
have in here of are we hitting the mark
in this program and and not uh making
sure that we're not excluding groups
whereas uh we're collecting that
information. Then household income of
course if we're looking at equity fund
issues this will help us with that area.
Veteran status and zip codes so that we
could find uh are we hitting urban and
versus rural.
Uh next [clears throat] slide please.
then some of the baseline and history.
So, um already recommendations are
coming forward for the patient
qualifications and there are four that
are codified in law and so ICD9 code or
ICD10 code, excuse me, I'm I'm I'm way
off. ICD10 codes. Yeah. Yeah. I I grew
up on HIV 1500 form. So you if you can
remember that, congratulations. Um but
on on these ICD codes, this would allow
us to track is this disorder related to
one of those four. Um diagnosis
duration, especially when we're looking
at acute, chronic or ter uh or or
treatment resistant conditions. uh the
treatment history because in treatment
resistant uh depression usually it's the
failure of two or more different
anti-depressant uh uh protocols and then
combant meds which would be if there's
any kind of medications that the patient
might be on that would have some contra
indication or interactions and baseline
severity. So again going back to the
research that I was sharing about some
of those tools then there could be a
scaled score that we could use as a
baseline then for for the interactions
and the integration. Next slide please.
For session logistics this would be the
data elements that would be for the
actual session and so there would be a
one to many relationship. There would be
many sessions for an individual going
back to the patient identifier, the date
of the session, uh tracking of
facilitator license, the product lot so
we can track the product uh the dosage
uh and and I would love to hear
everybody's thoughts on this as we talk
a little bit more about it. But uh it's
we I feel that it looks a little bit
more towards the uh actual dosing of a
molecule, not just the the biomass
itself. uh the administration mode of
the session. So was it done in an
individual or a multitude of like a
group session setting type where this
was done? Uh the MEQ. So this is again
going back to those mystical experience
questionnaire and the challenging
experience questionnaire. These are
self-reported from the individual that's
experiencing the psychedelic treatment.
And so having this kind of number to see
like was this was this dosing of the
mystical experience quotient high uh or
did this individual have challenging
experiences on this. Um I did see a hand
up so I want to like take a breath here
because thank you all for kind of
commenting. Now
>> Jane your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Yeah. Um, regarding dosage, um, I know
from my experience in, um, Oregon that
the
rule there is 5 milligram or, uh, five
grams, I mean, is the maximum dose
allowed under the state law. Um, and
that that comes from, I believe, um,
Terrence McKinn's said five, you know,
five grams is the heroic dose, right?
um his intent wasn't that five grams is
the
that's the minimum I believe heroic dose
right he's the he you know so I I I want
to ensure that we look at
that because I don't think five grams
um for me was
enough for me I mean
>> so I appreciate that. I think that that
I I would really like for you to
consider uh the dosage committee which I
believe is coming up later today
>> is having because
>> I just saw I I just saw a dosage I just
saw dosage there and I and that's one of
the things I want to make sure I um
>> bring up. So if this isn't the right
form for that I I I understand. Thank
you.
>> No, it's it's perfect and I appreciate
you sharing that. That's why when you
share that, it helps me to kind of get
you connected up with the right team
that are going to kind of be making
those those kind of discussions and
decisions. So, that's a fantastic thing
because your voice needs to be on that
committee. Um, on this one, what I would
love to kind of focus on is the research
that might show different dosage,
different higher doses or lower doses
and stuff is something that we can then
kind of inform that committee with. So,
thank you for that comment. I appreciate
that.
We have two more hands up and then some
comments in the in the chat. Uh I'll go
through the the hands up first.
Dan, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Um hello there. Um so on the dosing, um
am I am I understanding this correctly?
You guys are only going to focus on
psilocybin and you guys are not going to
focus on silosin. Um because the active
the active molecule that actually gets
you high is not psilocybin, it's
solosin. And out here in Oregon, we have
many growers that are growing and their
product is converting into solosin and
actually there's an emergency meeting
going on in Oregon trying to change the
regulation. So I highly recommend you
maybe reach out to Oregon.
>> Thank you for sharing. I I believe and
so again this is belief. So, please
know, don't take my uh word on this, but
I believe that the law for New Mexico
specifically does not include uh the
synthesis of it. So, I believe for that
reason, I think that we're focusing on
the psilocybin site. So, again, that's a
belief. Don't don't run out and say Dan
said this is the way that the law is,
but that would be something that the
dosing committee more than likely would
be looking at.
Ken, uh, we have some more hands raised
up, but I'll go through, uh, the next
speaker and then we'll read the chat.
>> James, your mic has been enabled. Please
speak uh, please unmute yourself to
speak.
>> Thank you. Just a couple thoughts on
this with uh, with dosage. I really like
the idea of milligrams and I do agree
with like I said before with salivosin
and that conversion and some of the
whole fruit does actually have salosin
in it already. And so when people do
take the whole fruit they will have
both. So just thoughts on that. Um
thoughts on disease states as we approve
those ICD10s. Will this form have
different for each disease state? Per
say PTSD has its own um you know
everybody would have its own form so
that we can differentiate that data. Um
so those were a couple thoughts that I
had. Um I like our stark but I would
like to also include uh dosage uh the
the the type. So if we has been um
alluded before if you powderize it like
in Oregon like I was trained um you know
are we doing that? Um I want to know are
they taking whole fruit by itself? Are
they taking the powderized? Are they
taking capsulated? Are they taking um
troes? Are they taking the chocolates?
You know just a thought on that as well.
That's the one I had so far.
>> I love that. Thank you very much for
that recommendation.
>> And and actually before we go further,
uh I just want to clarify one thing and
I put it into the chat. Um and this is
Dominic for those who are on their
phones. Um but I put it into the chat
and our definition of psilocybin as far
as the statute does include the active
metabolite psilocin. So when we are
talking in general, we don't need to
continue saying psilocybin andsosin. we
can just speak about psilocybin for the
purposes of how we move forward. So I
just wanted to make sure that people
actually do understand that that is one
of the definitions within the statute
and uh that was there for these exact
types of reasons. So just from a
language standpoint when we talk about
psilocybin it does include the active
metabolite solos.
>> Thank you for the clarification and and
for any correction if I misspoke on any
of that. So thank you.
Yeah, before we go uh back to the
handstand, I would want to read a few
things in the chat if that's okay with
you. Uh we have a comment from James. Uh
what about including dosage forms? Uh
Gregory said, "I have been working on a
very detailed dosage guidance paper and
would love some eyes on that. Not also
not all grams are equal." Uh Ian added
the dosage administration and clinical
practice committee on January 14th later
today is a propagation committee. Yes,
thank you.
>> Thank you for clarification. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Uh Eric Baka, the grams of dosage
being consumed isn't consistent across
all species. So dosage would actually be
based on actual psilocybin consumed. And
then Dominic uh just com has a comment
in the chat, but just uh clarified that
while speaking uh Dan Houston, oh that
is wrong. Please do not go off of
suicide. Very bad. But we address that.
Okay, I'll go back to the raised hands.
Ian, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
Uh, good morning everyone. My name is
Ian Dunn. I am also on the medical
psilocybin advisory board. I wanted to
talk because um, [clears throat] so we
already worked on trying to get you guys
the ICD10 at least from the patient
qualification committee. Um in terms of
dosage, what I was imagining um for that
committee was we were going to give
dosage ranges. So there was going to be
a subperceptual, a mild perceptual,
therapeutic, and then high and not
necessarily say you can only take up to
X number. Instead, leave it up to
provider specifications. So, um, we
wouldn't have that organ problem. But I
definitely do concur with the general
sentiment of acknowledging at least
within our, um, testing and laboratory
testing and things, the amount of
psilocin. If you don't know um psilicin
is so psilocybin is a prod drug of
psilicin which basic basically just
means psilocybin does nothing in your
body until it's converted by your body
to psilicin um which actually causes the
um hallucinogenic effects. So what
they're saying is sometimes mushrooms
have a sparse amount of psilicin in
them. Should we be using that chemical
as well in terms of measuring our dosage
for
um
research purposes because they are going
to have pharmacologically distinct
mechanisms.
Thank you. And I appreciate the
clarification on that one too. I've made
a note of that in here.
I think you're muted. Uh
>> I think uh thank you.
Uh I'm going to try to keep this dosage
thing as it relates to research and
development because [clears throat] one
of the things that we very very much
need
globally but we have access to execute
here um in relation to dosage is
understanding what is in a gram of any
given biomass. Um, [clears throat] as
Ian pointed out, salosin is the active
chemical that creates the psychedelic
experience. It is not the only chemical
in
any psilocybin containing mushroom. It
is a part of an ecosystem that builds a
unique experience.
>> [clears throat]
>> One thing to note, if you have a biomass
with high salosin content in in ratio to
high psilocybin,
your solosin is active in about 15 to 20
minutes. So that will come on more
rapidly and your psilocybin will
continue to uh [clears throat]
process in your gut biome
um and will extend that trip. So if you
have something that's just like all
silosin, it's very unstable. Those those
mushrooms will not last as long in
storage. Whereas psilocybin is very very
stable and will last a lot longer in
storage. So product [clears throat]
shelf life is something that we need to
anal analyze in this because if we have
a production chain that goes
uh harvest dry batch test return COA off
to market like we need to know that
there could be a variance in shelf life
based on what the chemical profile is of
that specific batch. And every genetic
that fruits in an instance is highly
unstable. So like you could have your
gamma decay that is harvested on 101 and
the 1026 harvest is going to be a
completely different alkyoid ratio. So
we need to be very very very clear about
what the input dosage is and then like
on the other side of things like
understand what the person's like set
and setting gut biomeal stability uh
mood for the day what their diet um who
they talk to in the morning you know
that that sort of thing all those things
can affect your experience so without
[clears throat] getting too deep into
that I think really un using this group
to understand what's in um any given
biomass. And also, not to go on too
long, Oregon did this whole wood lovers
thing. We [clears throat] cannot get
down go down this train of being like we
can't grow mushrooms on wood. Most
mushrooms grow on wood. Um they are
designed to bio like to tear down
organic matter. Like [laughter]
it's just um it's a misconception. We
can't get lost in misconceptions of
terminology such as wood lovers. whereas
wood lovers are a an unknown category or
clay of saloscopy mushrooms. Right? So
there are a lot of mushrooms that have a
lot of value outside of cubensus and I
want to make sure that we can maintain
the ability to work with those lesser
known species.
>> Thank you. Appreciate that.
>> And we have three more hands raised.
Denali, your mic has been enabled.
please unmute yourself.
>> Um, hi again everyone. I um had to step
out for a minute but think I'm following
this part of the conversation. I wonder
if it might be helpful uh given you know
uh Chair Jennings uh scope of what we're
we're hoping to talk about today is
maybe think about this particular issue
um as one of the very many case studies
in in um this issue
um
that demonstrates you know just that we
really need to be sure that we have
adaptive regulations. Um, I think in
terms of actual actually putting um into
practice the words of the subcommittee
and um continuous improvement, I think
that one of the the best things that we
can do is um recognize, you know, that
the these are areas that we are still
learning a tremendous amount about and
that the best thing that we can do to
ensure that our regulations are
responsive to what we know, but also
recognize that we don't know everything
and need to be able to choose to to make
changes where where necessary is to
build in really a structure for adaptive
regulations that incorporate new
evidence and and really do a good job of
ensuring that treatment remains
responsive as we continue to develop and
understand. Um that's all I wanted to
contribute.
>> Thank you.
>> You want to read the you want to read
the chat before we go to the next
reader? I mean,
>> yeah, that would be perfect. Uh, I think
let me see where we left off there.
>> I can I can find that. Uh, thank you.
There was a comment.
>> I think it was Eric Baka was the next
one.
>> Yeah, let's see. You're right. Yep. Uh,
Eric says, "Standard standardized
testing of fruit bodies for psilocybin
percentage calculating the the
conversion of psilocent in the body is
the only true dosage measurement." And
then Houston, uh, please look at the
studies, uh, and added a link in there.
And then Gregory, sorry for the
long-winded ramble. Also, yes to
adaptive, there is so much that is truly
unknown.
Okay.
Uh, next we have we have Desba. Please
un uh your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself.
>> Hi. So, I was just trying to see if I
can kind of synthesize what I've been
hearing so far just for the sake of like
putting a pin in this. Um I think this
is a good point in a moment um Dan that
we can kind of for the sake of um anyone
who's you know following where we're
trying to go with the norms and
understanding this committee is that you
know there's just like this huge river
of information that we're trying to
figure out and I'm seeing this is where
we're having these tributaries where the
research that I believe um you know the
starting out point is the language that
Denali is pointing out where the
adaptive flexibility this is where we're
standing at now this is where we're
going to look out towards the future of
our understanding and in that scope is
where um to Greg's point you know we are
looking at how the psilocybin is
converted and also has the psilicin
involved in that mushroom um which then
would eventually lead to the dosage
which is in is what he's talking about
what that looks like in terms of um
administering facilitating to um the
satin setting of what we're trying to
create, you know, long down into the
future. Um, but for anyone that might be
seeing where the research part of that
goes into that, that's this is this is
the beginning part of looking into these
different tributaries of these different
committees where those are going to
start kind of flowing into all of these
different territories down into um the
scope of what the advisory board is
going to um start pro providing, you
know, the regulations and the framework
and the structure.
Um, so this is, you know, thank you Dan
for facilitating this conversation of,
you know, getting started of where we're
at, where we're sliding these, um, this
information into these different
committees and what that would look like
for the future.
>> Beautifully said. Thank you very much,
>> James. Your mics has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you again, and I'll keep this one
simple. Um the word entourage comes to
mind here. Um there's a lot more things
in biomass than just the solosin
psilocybin things like biocysteine other
things that are actually in that whole
fruit are going to be down the line
again important but not currently I
don't think we break down the biomass
that extensively um I think we law and
we stick to that psilocybin mostly terms
and we also keep that in mind of solosin
and the three phases of action that I
want to remind everybody of that onset
very quick. The duration that's in that
middle, you know, how long is it going
to last for based off your dose does
matter and also what that genome is. So,
if you're taking different, you know,
genomes, they do matter. Um, but I think
really we focus back on this group on
certificate of analysis. I want to bring
that up. So, we make sure that, you
know, are we saying milligrams, which
I'm highly for, but in that certificate
analysis, is that's where it's going to
be important to say, you know, and um
the guy from Oregon, I think it's James,
is there a way you could share a
certificate of analysis with us?
And that's all. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. I appreciate that.
Yeah. And this uh as we're working on
this, this this is the data element. And
so we can look at different data
elements that we could add into data
collection uh and how we define those
things. Uh so that's perfectly fine. And
I love all the research that everybody's
bringing up. I really would as part of
the homework uh activities. I really
encourage everybody that has specific
research, you know, information about
what you brought up during this this
kind of phase here, please share it with
that email address, the medical
psilocybin email address, and that would
be fantastic. Please, if you're doing
that, make sure that it's coming into
the RACI committee so that we can bring
that in and that way we can talk about
that uh at next meetings cuz this is
exactly uh like I said Desa said it
perfectly. This is the whole way what
we're trying to do is get something kind
of started and then have this in such a
way that these teams, these committees,
this advisory board that we have
continues to look at new information,
new research and adapt and grow into
that. So absolutely this is kind of like
what I'm doing today is day zero as a
start to kind of gather things and then
all of the things everybody's bringing
up very valid to look at. But let's make
sure that if you have the research
behind that, please share that so that
we can add that in and uh just let me
know a little bit about it so that when
I bring that into our research kind of
list, that would be fantastic. I'll take
another beat here if there's some more
comments that came in in the chat.
I think Greg Evans has I have a whole
database of analytics for multiple
chemists. Happy to share my research.
Great. send it to the medical psilocybin
address that's on the screen. Um, and as
I said, for the sake of small
clarification and where this information
flows into propagation, which is next
meeting today, yes, this is kind of what
we're doing. This these are teasers.
This is so that if you're like, hey,
I've got to come to the next meeting.
This is exactly right. Cultivation would
be a wonderful meeting to go to
propagation, cultivation, and then also
dosing. So these meetings that that that
Ian brought up also these are the ones
please come to those and kind of share
that information and Houston says that
there is an Oregon psilocybin report
email if you want to see it. Make sure
Dan if you're sharing sharing it to the
medical psilocybin link.
Oh and thank you Donnie for sharing the
next meetings there. Again these are all
our meetings are kind of teasers again
for the next meetings. So these are good
if you're having like specific
information you'd like to share or
questions that you might want to raise.
these are the meetings to also come to
too. So get your voice out there and and
bring that up with us. So thank you.
And if we might jump back into the slide
deck, I only have a couple of more
slides to hit to kind of show and I
think that the next one would be the
adverse event reporting ones right
there. Thank you, Dominic, for sharing
that one. Uh again, just a starting
point. These will be something that we
can talk about add uh make changes to as
well. But on adverse report adverse
effect reporting, we would look at the
session identifier linked to that
session. Uh what the category was, was
it a physiological, was it
psychological, was it a behavioral? Um
so again to differentiate between
different things the event description
as a narrative the severity and I use
the recommendation to use the CTCA uh AE
uh recommendations as a way to say these
are the different types of uh adverse
effects that could happen and then the
rating scale across that on the severity
uh the intervention that was was
utilized in that adverse event. Uh and
then uh that way we could look at was
this a verbal deescalation or did it
require EMS transport
>> [clears throat]
>> uh if there is a suicidality uh that we
need to look at utilizing again another
type of a self-reported scale or
clinician reported scale and then the
duration of that adverse event. So was
it transient or was it something that
was persistent and so adverse effects
can take place at any point along the
way of the uh the dosage. So it could be
all the way from the actual dosage to
even after effects after the uh patient
would leave uh the the setting if this
was done at home. The same thing. So
just wanted to kind of bring those ideas
up. And then the last slide for this
will be the clinical outcomes which is
the followup integration and followup
being critical for this. Uh and so again
patient identifier linked back to
demographics. the date of integration uh
the setting type of where that
integration took place and then other as
appropriate uh baseline or measurements
that would go track back to baseline. So
for example if a matters or the PHQ was
used for depression or a PH PTSD score
or a GAD for example for general anxiety
and uh like I mentioned that substance
abuse the timeline followback or an
audit if it was for alcohol. So these
kind of things would be a way that we
could build into the system a way to see
is the treatment being affected
effective as we're doing this research
as well. So this is a like I said a very
ve very very rudimentary and very drafty
idea for data collection but I felt it
incumbent upon myself to show something
at least to bring to uh you group as a
as a committee in order to just start
with something and then that way at
least we can talk about it we can add to
it we can say why is this on here this
shouldn't be on here or or those kind of
things. So again, I wanted to bring that
to y'all and if there's discussion still
to have with these last few slides, uh
please I would love to hear it just as
you've done before. Again, if it's
thoughts afterwards, you can always
email and then if you're like, hey, I
need to go back and really review this.
They'll be back up on the psilocybin
medical psilocybin page at the DO in 5
to 10 days or so after this meeting. So
that way you can bring this down and
take a look at it more. Again, all these
are drafts. So uh anybody okay Gregory
thank you very much afterglow is a
phenomenon this is in the chat that I
believe can be directly tied to several
non-active component compounds which
potentiate neural health needs research
absolutely
any other thoughts comments things that
you want to um slings and arrows and
barbs at me or anything like Yeah,
I'll give again a little bit. Great.
Thank you very much, James. I see that
you've got your hand raised. Thank you,
>> James. Your mic has been en enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you. Um I'm interested. Um I was
looking through SB 219 and there's no um
language surrounding
um the questionnaire asking of other
psychoactive substances or other
medications used prior to the dosing
session. And I think um when dealing
with polypharmacological interactions,
it's imperative as a safety parameter to
investigate whether or not additional
psychoactive substances were used prior
to the dosing as a part of like an
adverse event reporting. So we can say
and pinpoint was it the actual medical
psilocybin that causes potential adverse
event or was it the I and I don't want
just a fantastical example. somebody
takes a shot of Jack Daniels prior and
then goes into the session. Not saying
that that will happen, but I think it's
imperative that we document other types
of uh substances.
So, thank you.
>> Thank you, James. And to just to kind of
uh add on to that what I had put in for
the clinical uh baselines uh and history
uh which was a slide two from that was
uh concomant meds and so things like
that that might be uh other medications
that might be effect but you're exactly
right that's on the demographic side so
that would be tied at the top level but
you're exactly right this would change
from session to session potentiality so
thanks for bringing that up I like that
comment so thank you very
and Shane I think has his hand up. Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Yeah. Um first just real quick Dominic I
sent you an email regarding my inability
to um put anything in the chat. Um I
also
want to talk about the adverse um
effects thing here. We need to be really
careful when we're saying adverse
effects because
in my experience um as an integration
coach some people have
a
traumatic experience
come up during their journey
but they receive healing for that
traumatic experience. So calling that an
adverse reaction [snorts]
by that they came up that they had an a
I don't want to use bad trip but that
they had a traumatic thing come up
during their um journey but that they
were healed of that. I don't I wouldn't
classify that as an adverse effect.
>> Thank you.
>> Right. Um, so
I I just want people to be to be careful
um of that um because like I I'm I'm
meeting with um uh veterans um group
later this week and he expressed that
thing. He's like, "Yeah, I've heard a
lot of people have really bad
um um trips or really bad um traumatic
things happen to them." I'm like, "Yeah,
but did they receive healing for that?"
So if they receive the healing then
don't call that adverse reaction
right. So I just you know when we're
when we're talking about adverse
reactions I just want people to be very
clear about that.
>> I appreciate that the chain and that's
good because uh the verbiage is going to
be important. Um I would love uh
recommendations to change because uh uh
instead of calling adverse effects
reporting uh because on that data
collection I imagined a way to put kind
of what the category was the severity
and an intervention and what was what
was done about that. So you're exactly
right. If there was something as you
said that came up that could have been
taken care of through healing that would
have been the intervention description
information about that. But you're
right, maybe the terminology adverse
effect is not the right terminology to
use. So I would love to like I said
let's you know something to kind of
consider to talk about and to say like
what kind of you know words are
important what kind of words would make
more sense instead of adverse effect. So
challenging. Thank you Despa as as one.
>> And we have some comments in the chat.
Um from James, can we add the poly
substance/poly pharmacy section of the
AD form? Gregory says uh to what Shane
is saying, I think the perception of
data and misunderstanding of the terms
is hugely important. Difficult and
challenging are very different concepts.
and from Desba uh challenging in
quotation mark is what I would sorry
quotation marks is what I would use.
James added uh adverse experiences
reaction form question mark and Gregory
challenging is a term that offers a path
towards growth was the final comment.
>> Thank you all very much. I appreciate
that because that's exactly what I was
hoping that we could kind of come from
this uh uh and so thanks for kind of
sharing these kind of things. Again,
that's what I said. Where's my blind
spots? Where are things? And so, I want
to kind of respect exactly what the
committee is thinking about. So, thank
you. I appreciate that. Um, and I see
Brenda has her hand up.
Your mic's been enabled. Please unmute
yourself to speak.
>> Brenda, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Brenda, if
>> Okay, there we go. It wasn't working. My
chat's not working either. Um, thank
you, Dan, for having um all of this
information. This is really uh
important. I've worked in many rehabs
and uh prior to having anybody come in
and and um uh you know sign paperwork
and all that uh having UAS before
administering any any other medications
is really important and so I think
having that um
u prior to um administering any uh
psilocybin
uh that would be one of the things that
would be um part of all of this. So I
think when we were getting into like um
when people are having these challenging
um issues uh during their journey um I
think that's a really important part is
making sure that people are
um
uh having a um
you know a medical uh doctor there to
make sure that they're um able to take
the medicine.
Thank you. I believe
>> there's one comment in the chat. Yep. Uh
James says, "I agree. Being a veteran
myself, wording does matter to a lot of
vet community."
>> Exactly.
>> Have hands up. We have one hand up.
Ben, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Yeah, Dan, thank you for the
conversation. Uh, I'm curious about the
data collection and how that extends to
preparation
and what the duration is and followup
after the fact. From a medical
standpoint, I know that cost and
billable hours and reimburs are all
issues. And my experience in more
indigenous practices is that the
preparation and then the time after is
as much the ceremony as anything else.
And often it's the reminder that life
itself is the ceremony. So I wonder how
that really works together whether it's
followup for a a challenging event
because sometimes you don't get the
answer in that experience itself
sometimes that comes after the fact and
how you really bring that into your life
how you bring that into practice so I
wonder how those two worlds can merge
and same in preparation when you learn
about people's lifestyles whether
they're chronic pot smokers or
alcoholics olics as well as what the
concominant drugs that they're on. All
of those play a piece. Yeah. As well as
the mindset and the preparation and
going into those experiences. I think
that it's important to collect data on
that and to have both the preparation
and setting of intention and some of
these more subtle things. How do you
weave that into the scientific as well
as then what's often called just
integration? And I feel like integration
can be a little dismissive. Often it's a
a one-time conversation and we got our
facts or you know how are there support
teams to really walk with people and
bring these changes and and this into
our communities and back into our homes
and back into our lives.
>> Thank you Ben for those comments. I
appreciate that. That's very good to
consider too. Thank you.
Gregory has a comment in the chat. I
think there is a strong case for access
to specific dosages without a doctor
present but that is for another
committee.
>> Yes, thank you.
>> One more comment from Desba for the sake
of the meeting proposing the board and
future marketing education. uh I'm
visual. I think a color-coded flowchart
would be a great to see how research is
involved in each step of this process
and the committees and feedbacks uh into
the dynamic of the whole especially from
when we tend to go into the weeds on
certain tributaries.
>> Yeah, thank you very much. Yeah, the
idea that I have kind of on this is that
because there are all the other
committees that are makes up this uh
board is that if I could utilize this
committee as a way to kind of share
these kind of research tools can inform
those uh committees and the work that
they do and you're exactly right it may
may not be a spec you know flowchart in
one direction or the other but that's
exactly what my intentionality is on
this. Yes, it is homework that's part of
my job too. So, my job is to try to like
bring in as much from what y'all have in
comments and suggestions and ideas and
then weave that together, bring that
back to y'all so that we can then say
this is now what we've talked about from
before. Here's the updates and changes
to the best that I have and then we can
then say great now let's put this to a
vote or discussion and such. So,
absolutely. Thank you.
James says in the chat with integration
section what including as section on
types of integration virtual in person
or other. So for example uh in the data
elements that I had kind of just
proposed about the uh the clinical
outcome uh was that uh information but
it was part of the session. So you're
exactly right. I don't have anything in
there about where that clinical outcome,
the followup, the integration took
place. Uh, actually, no, it does.
Setting type. I apologize. I'm looking
at it now. So, on that uh page, yes,
thank you very much. It was the
Keep going back uh forward.
Oh, went up. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Donna's got the scroll going on. So if
you'll Donnie, if you go to the very
last slide of the deck and then back up
one.
There you go. So you're exactly right,
James. I tried to include something in
there about what the setting type uh had
had looked like. Was a clinic, home,
retreat center, virtual, something like
that. So
okay. And so I would love to kind of hit
the last phase. Uh so Don if you
wouldn't mind going to the very last
slide which is future discussions and so
um what I have been thinking about other
things that we could work with on this
committee. So I think the first ones
that I would like to really try to focus
on is some of that you know continuing
gathering the research that y'all can
share with me and I'll continue to
update and add that and to make it in a
much better looking format uh as Desa
has recommended because it needs to be
something that can be utilized by the
advisory board and the committees and
such and everybody else can see that in
easy form. uh but some of the other
things that in the data but the other
things that I had looked at was um if if
we would need to consider ideas for go
no-go checklists. Um I do a lot of uh
rocket launches with uh with high school
students and so I do mission control and
so one of the things that we have is
kind of like uh we call it a F FRR
flight readiness review and so these are
things to say yep these are all in place
and if all these things are in place
then we're a go we can actually we can
actually launch. Uh, and so I'm curious
if the committee might be interested in
talking about a go no-go checklist for
lots of different reasons. One would be
for just the program in general. Like
these are the things that the committees
must have in order to to to say that we
can move forward with this. So, it's
just a good way for us to kind of as as
the rest of the board kind of think
about uh what everybody wants to make
sure that is in place. uh and these are
the things that must be in place to
ensure that we're doing things safely
and and and correctly. Uh so this is a
future discussion but I just want people
to kind of think about that. Um other is
outcome monitoring and porting. So how
would we actually do good outcome
monitoring and reporting? Uh what does
emergency preparedness and response look
like? Uh and how do we of course provide
training information out to the field
for that emergency response? Uh again,
part of our uh responsibility of this
committee is patient to community
education. Uh and I do mean that from a
community standpoint because we want to
make sure that this is messaged
correctly uh received well, those kind
of things. So this is something and
these are again going back to the
homework. This is one of the big things.
And then of course research and
evaluation practices. So uh as was asked
earlier, would this committee be
informing some of that research and
evaluation practices? My hope is yes.
Those are some of the things that this
committee could work on and to propose
that we could bring to the board as a
whole. Uh and so those are just like I
said one some of the things I would like
to keep everybody thinking about as we
move forward. And then I'll just need
you know if you're like that's exactly
what we need to do then you probably
will know I'll probably say great I know
somebody who's going to have some
homework. uh because I would love it for
somebody who takes that passionate
interest in that to be able to provide
some of that info back to this committee
uh to to kind of share and so that we
can just because I I'm not going to be
doing all of it, all of the work and all
the talking. I just wanted to kind of
get this first one launched and so that
we could kind of set the flow, the tone,
the norms and such. Uh and so before I
take another break, I see that Greg is
one.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So yeah, thank you Dan. Uh Gregory
says throwing one other high level
considerations how or what guidance can
we provide to the regulatory process for
analytics and reporting question mark.
>> Exactly. And that's uh kind of what the
data system that I have kind of showed
is kind of where I wanted to kind of go
with that one. So that's the analytics
and porting side that I'm hoping that we
can provide re uh recommendations to to
the board and then subsequently to the
the program. something. And uh so at
this point, that's kind of where I just
wanted to kind of kind of share a little
bit about what I'm hopeful for and some
of the things that I've done in my
homework so that I could share with
y'all to get us launched and started. Uh
and so we still have about 30 minutes
left of this. So I wanted to give plenty
of time for me shutting up and then
letting public comment take place at
this time. So this time is your time.
And so what I would love is like I said
we have 30 minutes until the end. So
when we do hit 11 the meeting will end
but I would love if you have comments
that you would like to share of a
general note anything that you would
like to talk about and I won't be
probably responding to most of them
because uh I may not be able to respond
to every one of those kind of things but
this will just be a great way to kind of
share and talk and I'll take notes as we
go if it's something pertaining to this
committee. Um, but I would appreciate if
you would be able to have your comments
to a three minute uh timeline so that we
could hear from everybody if there would
be somebody that's wants to share
something. Um, so I would just again
just as we've done before use the hand
raise feature uh there on your toolbar
in order to get in the queue and uh then
we'll go ahead and unmute your
microphone as you come up in the queue.
So, thank you and I appreciate number
one if you do have to jump off at this
time uh because you don't have a comment
to say I do number one thank you so much
for your time today because I know that
it's hard to take time out of your day
and especially on Fridays. So, thank you
for being here with me. I hope it was
worth your time. I hope you can see the
vision we do have for this committee. Um
I hope that the work that we do will be
beneficial. I hope that I can be a a
good chair for you for this and to bring
your voices to the board as a whole. Um,
and I need you to kind of hold me to
that. So, please kind of keep me to that
and uh I don't want to say don't be
afraid to challenge me, but do it in a
kind way, but challenge me on the things
that you're thinking that I'm not uh
bringing your voice to be heard on. And
so, I'll make sure that the committee as
a whole gets to hear it and then they
get to decide as well. So, if I'm
falling down on that, please let me
know. Um, and, uh, keep an eye out for
our next meeting that we'll have and
then we'll start to get onto our regular
schedule. So, I appreciate that. That's
what I wanted to say. And so, now I'll
open it up for the public comments for
everybody. Thank you.
>> There's one hand then. Uh, Shane, your
mic has been enabled. Please unmute
yourself to speak.
>> Yeah. Um, so we've done a little bit of
discussion about integration and as I
said earlier, I'm an integration coach.
Is there a forum
um in this group um where where they're
going to be discussing
integration specifically? Um right. So,
we've got dosage, we've got uh end of
life, we've got a bunch of that other uh
but I don't see one that seems to be the
right place to talk about integration
and what the
board is going to recommend um or
require or
um
just anything around integration. And
this and a second thing is Dan um can
you put a way to contact you directly in
the chat or if if you don't mind so that
if we have um you know questions or
something specifically for you that we
can reach out to you.
>> Sure. Thank you for that. And I'll go
ahead and put that thank you very much
on that email address. There is my email
address and so you can simply send it
and just say get this over to Dan. uh in
that way because again this is you know
this is a public forum and so even those
kind of requests and everything get uh
tracked and logged because this is uh an
open and transparent process. So please
use that email address that would be
fantastic they will get it to me and
then I get to respond back to you and it
will still continue to copy to the
medical psilocybin uh link so that that
way it's all tracked and logged. So
thank you very much for that. Okay. And
then like I said about the integration,
is there some
forum that's going to be specific to
that?
>> Dan, I can I think I can answer that.
And Ian is also on the f on the call, so
if he has a disagreement or a different
place for it, but to me, the integration
aspect would go in with dosage
administration and clinical practice
because that would be a part of the
protocols and the process for the
overall treatment.
Okay, we have another hand up.
Gregory, your your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> Just need rambling again. Um, I actually
wanted to hear Dan Husen House ramble. I
have very specific question
that ties into a little seed I want to
plant in the research community. Um Dan,
if you're [clears throat] still on, have
you
>> done any
>> Yeah, Greg. Dan actually had uh said
that he had to drop off. Uh that was
earlier at about 10:00. So, um but if
you want to if you if you want to send
your question to us at our at the
medical psilocybin email, we will
forward it to him. I will definitely
like I'm writing a big old analytics
research summary of what I'm doing so
that you can just kind of have that. Um
but but what I'm sorry to cut you off
Dominic.
>> Not a problem. I was just saying that
we'll get your question to him. So
>> Oh, he'll hear from me.
>> Um mostly like so Dan is in Oregon.
There's another guy in Oregon that I
think would be really valuable in this
conversation. and his name is Jordan
Jacobs. In Colorado, there's a gentleman
by the name of Ian Bowlinger who um I
would love to bring into this
conversation. He um if nobody knows who
he is, he is one of the adviserss for um
the uh god damn I can't I'm not even
remembering the name of the company, but
they run the psychedelic cup in Denver.
Um but he kind of like designed all the
analytics around that. Um but
specifically what we're not looking for
that I think we should be looking for in
diverse species is beta carbolines.
Betacarbolines are uh
hello pharmacologists who wants to chime
in. um [clears throat]
uh chemicals that work as MAI inhibitors
uh specifically like harm and harm where
there are reports of harm being found in
psilocybin containing mushroom biomass.
When you have something like that
naturally occurring in uh in a single
species, you're going to have a
potentiated
uh like a massively potentiated
experience like um if I take a cubensus
at 1 g and I take uh banisteropsis cappy
or seran um as like a ma uh potentiator
uh you know you're turning your 1 g
experience into a 3 to 4
level experience perceptually. So like
if we're serving mushrooms and we're
just oh this has a gram of solicin
equivalent and it doesn't really take
into account unmeasured
uh compounds. I think we're doing oursel
a big old chaotic disservice.
But that's like how we've been doing it,
you know, like here's five grams of
mushrooms. Thanks Terrence. And then
like uh you know we have people like
Paul Stammitz that published paper from
a reputable university that says a micro
dose is 250 milligrams of something but
what what is it?
Anyways, um I'd love to hear from more
of the uh pharmarmacologists around that
those types of effects and get more
research uh up
and anybody else have their hands up? I
don't see anybody else's. So, if you
would like to get in the queue, make
sure you raise your hand, please.
>> James, your mic has been enabled. Please
unmute yourself to speak.
>> Thank you. to kind of piggyback on uh
James Brown's earlier comment in regards
to being um looking into the research.
Uh obviously we know science is always
changing and we need to be very mindful
of it as we develop and look at new
emerging papers. Just because something
is published does not mean it's correct.
[laughter]
And so I think it's really important for
us to be flexible as a community, accept
what the data has to say, and then look
at the reproducibility factor. And with
that being said, um, another quick t
point that I'd like to, uh, suggest, and
we didn't really talk about it much, is
as a harm reduction standpoint, I think
it's really important to really focus on
the deidentifier factors with our, uh,
medicals psilocybin patients. It's
really important that we uh abide by
HIPPA and make sure that those who are
receiving these medicines are protected
anonymous so that potentially if they
are an employee uh or within a
organization that doesn't necessarily um
uh agree with medical psilocybin that
they're protected and I think that's
very important. So, thank you for
lending an ear and I'm really excited
about this committee.
Dan, I'm gonna read a few comments in
the chat. Um, from Eric, great meeting.
I like where this is beginning. Greger
says, "You're an you are amazing, Dan."
Uh, Denali wrote, he also dropped his
email in the chat and that's for uh dan
rosecityabs.com.
And then Eric says, "I think what we are
really talking about here is DMT." Just
saying.
Go back to the hands that are raised.
We have James Brown. Your mic has been
enabled. Please unmute yourself to
speak.
>> Thank you again. And this will be my
last time for today, so I could keep
talking. I'm sure.
One thing I was going to bring up to the
my idea on this too was um with the
committee, who's going to be in charge
of besides the Department of Health, of
course, fielding those complaints?
Something to think about. um you know
when the department of health gets a
complaint um what I would like to see is
is uh root cause analysis like um esbar
we call it in medical terms right um you
know what are we going to do with that
um and then can we committee members be
part of that type of root cause analysis
correction or esbar with the department
of health of course you know um to offer
more suggestions and of course
corrections and and just best practices
and what we can get back to reduce the
harm if any is caused at all. And to,
you know, again, point back to the
literature. Um, these are very, very
amazing medicines that are going to come
up to New Mexicans. A lot of education
needs to come out to, uh, the general
public who's not aware of these things.
Um, I work in an area where we see a lot
of these things when they first hit the
communities. Um, a lot of a lot of
uneducated things can happen. a lot of
uncircumstantial
outcomes can happen and and we don't
want those. And so we want to kind of
focus and how do we get ahead of that.
So I want to see proactivity on how we
can see us get ahead of building these
type of things and getting out our
education to the communities as well as
the the providers who are very excited.
But the you know the comm community the
community is going to come out and say
what what is this and and we need to be
ready and so what what are we going to
have? Is there also um something that we
can produce and start thinking about as
far as resources for for those
communities? And thank you so much. I'll
end it with that.
>> Denali, your mic has been enabled.
Please unmute yourself to speak.
>> [clears throat]
>> Um, thank you so much, uh, Chair
Jennings and everyone for the
conversation today and starting so much,
um, good work of this committee. I I'm
kind of curious because I'm still trying
to wrap my head around the scope of the
committee and how it'll interact with
with others since um, continual
improvement.
um a lot a lot of the the mission I
think of this committee will be um put
to work once we have baseline
regulations and we have a program. Um I
think there's there's a lot of work to
be done to make sure that our
regulations allow for that. As I was
talking earlier about flexible adaptive
lean regulations are going to be the
best way that we can we can then make
changes that are necessary. But I'm I'm
kind of curious if it might fit within
the scope of this committee since um
related more to the research end than
the continuous improvement to be kind of
a holding place for research needs that
emerge in other committees. I mean just
in the early meetings that we've had
there are a couple of things that have
been identified by committees and it it
may be that within the membership of
that committee there's enough resources
to to do the homework as we were talking
about a few times during this this
meeting of those issues. But maybe
that's something that fits within the
role of this committee as a way to
support the other committees and do a
deeper dive on issues that are
identified when they are um that is my
only contribution. Thank you so much.
your mic has been enabled. Please unmute
yourself to speak.
>> Hi. Yeah. Uh yeah, Denali. And then I
think that was kind of where I was going
with the flowchart. I'm seeing where all
of these and and the comment that I was
trying to integrate with your
flexibility and adaptive earlier was
just you know I'm seeing this flow of
all this information and where does it
kind of start migrating into these other
tributaries of the different committees
and that was what what was the
suggestion um to put a a more visual cue
as to where does the research flow back
into the committee and where does it go
and how does it look in terms of for me
specifically, but I'm sure everyone
else, how does that research then inform
feedback into the committees? And I
think that that last commenter um made a
good point about, you know, what where
is when the fallout andor improvement um
for our own challenging experience as a
committee um I not a committee, as a
board and regulations, where does that
where does that information go? um where
the trees, to use the river analogy,
where the trees get caught and
everything else, how do we clean it up
and how do we maintain the flow of of of
this medicine to the rest of the state.
There's one comment in chat from
Gregory.
Excuse me. Plus one on that cross
committee dependency tracking.
Thank you very much. And uh I don't see
any other hands raised, but I do want to
kind of let that kind of settle because
I do appreciate those comments,
especially uh Denali and Desma on that.
Um, I I I I think that's a very uh good
way and Nemo's analogy to make that uh
kind of kind of put that in the story
mode makes a lot of sense. Um I love the
idea that if other committees may you
know have like here are some research
that we've used that we could be the
repository of that and consequently if
there are things that the committees uh
are needing uh in the research
categories that may not exist or they
don't have access to that or or we could
bring it to this committee and there are
could be the experts in this committee
uh that could say great here's the
research that you need to look at uh and
and to help us uh understand and to
implement some of those things. So, I
love that fact. Um I I never even
considered that. So, I appreciate that
and I would love to be able to have a
good two-way flow back from committee to
committee uh and especially to support
those committees. So this this committee
to me always felt like a very good
support role and to to be the ones that
can can help ensure that all the work
that the other committees are doing um
is backed up and supported and and
assisted. So I I love those thoughts
that y'all brought up. So um but again,
we still have until 11 scheduled. Uh,
but we'll we'll be here if you have any
questions or comments, but if there are
none, then I would love for us to be
able to you can log off at any time. So,
>> and Dan, uh, before people start logging
on off is, uh, if we could set what
exactly for the next date. I know it was
suggested earlier, two weeks, but, uh,
that is up to you and the the group
here. Um, but uh I just want to make
sure that we have that confirmed prior
to the meeting ending. So, uh,
>> I would I I would if if on y'all's
schedule because again I defer also to
the rest of the committees and the board
uh because I uh I don't see anything on
the calendar on my side, but I might not
see everything. Um but uh if the 23rd at
the same time is available, I would like
to continue having this kind of cadence
uh moving forward if that's possible.
>> So what I would just suggest is if
there's anybody who has an objection for
the meeting uh continuing and being on
Friday the 23rd starting at 9:00, uh go
ahead and say it now. Otherwise, we'll
take that as a consensus and move
forward. And we do realize just just so
everybody does know that not everybody
can always make every meeting. We do
understand that there will be occasional
times where individuals cannot. Um but
uh you know we try to do the best to do
that but I think having a regular
cadence is good and and so we do have
that space available. So I'm not seeing
any negatives. I did see a bunch of
thumbs ups. So uh unless you have an
objection Dan we will schedule those.
Just so everybody knows, one of the
things that we are doing from the
department standpoint is so that we're
not flooding people with lots and lots
of emails is we are batching all of the
the meetings and the links similar to
what we did for the first one. And we'll
be sending those out in batches on a
regular basis. And so we just have a
couple more going on right now. And then
we will do that. But for those people
who are here, you can pencil in on your
calendar that we'll schedule this
meeting, the next one, for Friday the
23rd at 9:00 a.m.
>> Perfect. Thank you very much. Appreciate
you doing that.
>> Again, there are a couple of comments in
the chat I want to read for you. Uh
let's see, we have one from Gregory. Uh
Dan Jennings, is there anything not
covered that you would like to see from
us prepared prior to the next meeting?
And from James, one of the areas of
research in the future will be the
review of literature on additional
health indications for the use of
psilocybin.
>> Thank you. And uh to answer that last
question there, um so the the last
things I would like for you to be able
to do again, we've talked about a data
collection system and we've talked about
the uh potential of the research that
I've gathered, but it's of course just
what I've gathered. So I would a couple
of homework activities would be continue
sending to the medical psilocybin email
address any research studies that you
would like to be considered to add it to
the list. Uh what I'll be doing is being
bring up we'll have a a certain time
frame during our meetings to bring up
here are the recommendations and then
again we'll let the committee then look
at those recommendations and then come
back with comments and suggestions back
from those before we add them on to the
list. again the list that I provided
you'll be able to see this entire slide
deck when it gets posted up to the do
site. So please do review that so you
can see what I've collected in the data
elements. So the homework really would
be that uh if there's anything in the
data elements that you're interested in
in commenting on and then subsequently
other activities as I said in future you
know discussions and thoughts would be
those kind of things that Tommy just had
up on the slide there our
responsibilities. So, that's kind of our
our area uh of what we're working on.
So, if there's something that's in there
that you're like, I would really like to
dig into that, then that would be
something also to either share at the
email address to say, I would like to
take a part of this. Here's some
information on that. Here's what we
could do. And then and or bring that up
at our next meeting because I'll have
some time at the beginning where we'll
be able to say, is there anything that
we need to work on that somebody would
like to take on? uh because we'll have a
lot of we need to work on this but we'll
now start to move into the we need to
work on this and I'm willing to work on
this will be the next thing. So uh
that's kind of the the homework for this
committee. So when we meet in two weeks
that's going to be our our kind of beats
that we'll have at that time. So I hope
that helps.
There you go. Thank you Dominic for
putting in the chat so the medical
psilocybin and put RACI. So, our new
official acronym for this committee and
that way it'll get directed to the right
place. It'll make it easier for
everybody out there. So, thank you very
much. I'm sorry I'm going to be flooding
y'all's inbox up there.
>> That's perfectly fine. We're used to
that. So,
>> yeah. [laughter]
>> Great. Well, again, thank you all very
much for being here. I again cannot
thank you enough. I'm humbled for having
you all here with me today. And I hope
to see you again in two weeks for our
next meeting. And bring bring your
friends. Bring your friends that this
let's make this a big party event next
Friday or next two Fridays from now. So,
thank you all.
>> Great. Well, and we'll go ahead at this
point. We'll close the meeting. So,
thank you everybody for attending and uh
we look forward to seeing you soon. Um
Dan, if you want to hold for a moment.
Got it.